

### Research Interest

My research interests primarily encompass Information Retrieval (IR) and Question Answering (QA). I aim to explore how language, whether in conversations, audio, or text, can be represented as question + external information = answer. My specific areas of focus include Open-Domain Question Answering, Fact Verification, and addressing the challenge of Hallucination or Confabulation in responses.

## **Education**

#### **Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology**

Seoul, S.Korea

M.S. IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Advisor: James Thorne

Mar. 2023 - Present

University of California, Berkeley

Berkeley, CA USA

B.A. IN STATISTICS

Aug. 2012 - Aug. 2017

## **Publications**

#### **Detrimental Contexts in Open-Domain Question Answering**

**EMNLP Findings** 

PHILHOON OH, AND JAMES THORNE

Sep. 2023

• In The 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, 2023

#### **Knowledge Corpus Error in Question Answering**

**EMNLP Findings** 

YEJOON LEE, PHILHOON OH, AND JAMES THORNE

Sep. 2023

• In The 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, 2023

# **Work Experience**

SK Inc. C&C Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER & PL

Jan. 2019 - Feb. 2022

- Developed NLP framework based on Pytorch for various NLP models and subsequent tasks.
- Designed pipelines for NLP tasks including MRC, ODQA, Keyword Extraction.
- Implemented automated pipeline for Korean Text Crawling and Pre-processing.
- Led NLP Keyword Extraction project.

#### Anemone Boutique LLC Santa Monica, CA USA

MARKETING ANALYST

Oct. 2017 - Mar. 2018

- · Analyzed the impacts of different marketing strategies.
- Implemented time series analysis (SARIMA) on previous quarters data to predict future sales.

# **Projects**

### Korean ODQA Project Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER

Jul. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Developed a Korean ODQA (Open Domain Question Answering) feature.
- Achieved performance improvements on datasets, including Korquad v1, AI common sense, and the XX hospital dataset.

## Chatbot PoC Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER

Jul. 2021 - Sep. 2021

- Demonstrated the Open-Domain Question Answering (ODQA) feature to one of the largest hospitals in Korea, the client
- The ODQA feature was integrated as an NLP feature through a PoC.

### Survey Project Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER & PL

Jul. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Developed a survey feedback tool for the SK SUPEX Council (Consultative Panel within SK Group).
- Implemented the Keyword Extractor module to collect feedback from anonymous ethical surveys.

NLP Framework Gyeonggi-do, S.Korea

NLP ENGINEER Jan. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Participated in developing an integrated NLP framework based on PyTorch.
- Designed a new architecture to support various NLP models based on tasks and features.
- Developed unit tests for the framework using the pytest module.

## **Honors & Awards**.

2023 **2nd Place**, 2023 Al Graduate School Challenge

2017 **Manga Cum Laude**, High Distinction in General Scholarship at graduation

Seoul, S.Korea Berkeley, CA USA